<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wireguard on reticulating splines</title><link>https://sbarbett.github.io/reticulating-splines/tags/wireguard/</link><description>Recent content in Wireguard on reticulating splines</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sbarbett.github.io/reticulating-splines/tags/wireguard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying an OCI Pi-hole with Terraform</title><link>https://sbarbett.github.io/reticulating-splines/posts/terraform-oci-pihole/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sbarbett.github.io/reticulating-splines/posts/terraform-oci-pihole/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="deploying-an-oci-pi-hole-with-terraform">Deploying an OCI Pi-hole with Terraform&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The other day, I wrote about deploying a Pi-hole on an Oracle Cloud VM alongside Unbound and WireGuard. In that post, I explained how to set everything up manually through the web interface and CLI. This time, I wanted to automate the deployment using a shell script and OCI&amp;rsquo;s Terraform module.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="terraform">Terraform&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Terraform is an infrastructure-as-code tool that lets you define and provision infrastructure through configuration files. Instead of manually setting up resources, you can describe them in a script, and Terraform will handle the provisioning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setting Up a Pi-hole with WireGuard on an Always Free Oracle Cloud VM</title><link>https://sbarbett.github.io/reticulating-splines/posts/oracle-cloud-unbound-pihole/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sbarbett.github.io/reticulating-splines/posts/oracle-cloud-unbound-pihole/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="setting-up-a-pihole-with-wireguard-on-an-always-free-oracle-cloud-vm">Setting Up a Pihole with Wireguard on an Always Free Oracle Cloud VM&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>About a week ago, I discovered that Oracle Cloud offers a free tier of virtual machines—not in the AWS &amp;ldquo;free for a year&amp;rdquo; sense, but free indefinitely (allegedly). The x86 instances come with 1GB of RAM and 1 vCPU, which isn’t much, but it’s enough for some basic workloads. I like to think of it as a Raspberry Pi Zero in the cloud.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>